Sunny Singh

1026 Bent Branch St, Gastonia, NC 28054 | +1 (516) 537-8258 | hello@sunnyis.me | http://sunnyis.me

Summary

Experienced and passionate web developer with extensive programming and web design skills. I am able to function independently on multiple projects and am fast and willing to learn something new.

Skills

Coding languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSON, XML, SQL/MySQL, PHP, Java

Libraries/frameworks: Laravel, WordPress, Bootstrap, ¡Query, Less

Source control: Git

Server management: Apache, Unix, Vagrant, SSH, FTP Operating systems: Mac OS X, Windows, Linux, Android Software/Tools: Adobe Photoshop, Microsoft Office

Certifications: Microsoft Office Excel 2010, Microsoft Office Access 2010

Experience

WIX Filters
Web Marketing, Web Development
June 2012 - Present
Gastonia, NC

- Saved the company thousands of dollars by rebuilding the website's timeline so that it no longer depended on Adobe Flash Player (removing the need to outsource the development). Coded in HTML, CSS, and jQuery.
- Edited product images with Adobe Photoshop by removing backgrounds, adjusting color and saturation, cropping, and saving to various sizes and formats.
- Added, deleted, and updated store locations for the website with Microsoft Access database software.
- Managed users for the online training program, WIX eLearning, and created diplomas that were framed and shipped by a third-party.

Ninjality

Co-founder, Lead Developer January 2014 - Present http://ninjality.com

A small web company startup. We work on multiple client requests and internal projects, including:

- A redesign for an upcoming technology news site (logo, WordPress theme).
- A queue system for a popular YouTube channel's website (front-end, PHP, MySQL).
- A social network (front-end, Laravel, Git, MySQL).
- A note-taking web app (front-end, Laravel, MySQL).
- Various design work (i.e. brand logos, banners, wallpapers).

There is extensive use of front-end and server-side languages, along with popular tools. All recent projects use modern coding paradigms (e.g. MVC) and use responsive layouts.

Personal Website

Creator

August 2011 - Present

http://sunnyis.me

Portfolio-style website to display my skills, projects, articles, and contact information. Built with:

- An HTML5/CSS3 responsive layout.
- The Less CSS preprocessor.
- Semantic.gs grid framework.
- WordPress CMS for managing content and writing articles.
- CSS @font-face for typography and icons.

Mediterranean Grill Kebab (Hewlett, NY)

Website Development, Website Management

January 2010 - 2012

Designed and developed a website to provide the Greek restaurant's customers a place to view menus, obtain information, find directions, and print out coupons. I used:

- Semantic and valid HTML to markup the site.
- CSS along with performance techniques such as CSS sprites to style to the site.
- jQuery to power some of the UI elements such as a slider for product images, and a modal box for enlarged views of menus.
- PHP to include common elements (e.g. header, footer) on multiple pages.

OWL Art Center

Website Management

April 2009 - 2012

Hewlett, NY

Responsible for continual maintenance of an art gallery company's website such as keeping information up-to-date and creating new pages for artists. Was an already made website, thus it required knowledge of:

- Drupal, a PHP content management system and framework.
- FTP for accessing and uploading files.
- Photoshop for updating schedules.

Relevant Experience

STARS Program

Charlotte, NC

Part of the STARS program at UNC Charlotte, designed to allow students to give back to the community of computing. Was given leadership roles in assisting students to learn coding fundamentals such as logic truth tables and basic HTML/CSS.

Music - Clarinet, Bass Clarinet

Hewlett, NY

Member of school's band and wind ensemble since grade 4 up until grade 12. Performed at All-County Nassau Music Festival for 3 years based on outstanding NYSSMA solo scores for both the clarinet and bass clarinet instruments.

Education

University of North Carolina at Charlotte

Degree: B.A. in Computer Science Concentration: Web Development Anticipated Date of Graduation: 2016

References are available upon request.